Leo：From the bottom of our hearts, we promise that from here on out
Vanessa의 위협이 사라진 지 3개월 후
It's already been three months since the crisis that Vanessa threatened the world with was averted...
Leo：저희는 향후 고대문명을 비밀리에 사용하는 것이 아닌,
A.R.C. stated that they would abolish the Library's facilities
A.R.C.는 Library의 사용을 폐지했고
Leo：and will be transparent with all the content of our research
Leo：연구 내용에 있어서도 모든 것을 공개하며
and use other types of server technology to replace the operations of the virtual internet
지금은 다른 서버 기술로 정신 네트워크 운영을 대신하게 됐다.
Leo：by making it available to the public
Leo：투명성이 높은 경영 방침을 지향하도록 하겠습니다.
Leo：Starting today, we will implement serious changes to our internal structure
Leo：또한, 사내 개혁 실시를 통하여
Leo：For the development of society and humanity
Leo：사회와 인류 발전에 있어서도
Of course, lots of people found this unacceptable and denounced the organization
수많은 사람들이 이를 받아들이지 못하고 현실을 지탄하고 있다.
Leo：we will seriously reconsider our position in society and the direction we are headed...
Leo：저희의 사회적 입지와 방향성에 대해 다시 한번 재검토하는 계기를 마련할 수 있도록...
Especially those who lost their loved ones as a result of what happened
특히 사랑하는 사람을 잃어버린 피해자들은 더더욱..
But after a period of time most people returned to their normal lives
그래도 대부분의 사람들이 어느 정도 시간이 지난 후 평소의 일상으로 다시 돌아오고 있다.
Time gradually diluted all that had occurred
시간이 흘러가면 이 모든 것 또한 잊혀져갈 것이다.
After graduating from university, NEKO became a professional streamer musician
NEKO 씨는 아카데미를 졸업한 후, 편곡 전문 스트리머가 됐다.
Besides her normal content of music, games and random gossip
음악말고도 게임이나 가십 거리 등등 폭넓은 활동을 벌이고 있다.
NEKO#ΦωΦ：Yo-ho! NEKO's here!
NEKO#ΦωΦ：야호~! NEKO 등장!
she also started a new series
새롭게 개설한 채널에서는
where she actively goes out to help the victims that were affected by Vanessa
Vanessa 사건의 피해자들을 돕는 활동을 벌이고 있다.
Victim：We don't need help from you internet addicts. Please, go away...
피해자：당신들 같은 네트워크 중독자의 도움 따위는 필요 없어요. 돌아가주세요...
Although she is constantly rejected, she never gives up
수없이 거절당해도 포기하지 않고
She used money she made from her music and streams to set up a foundation
음악과 방송으로 번 돈으로 자선단체를 설립해서
that donates to the people affected and related illnesses
피해자들과 후유증을 앓고 있는 사람들을 위해 모금 활동을 벌이고 있다.
Xenon started playing with a band again and got back on the stage to perform
Xenon은 밴드 활동을 다시 시작하며 무대로 돌아왔다.
NEKO can always be seen among the crowd
관중석에서는 언제나 NEKO의 모습이 보인다.
NEKO#ΦωΦ：Not bad~!
NEKO#ΦωΦ：수고했어~!
As for Xenon's sister Shannon,
Xenon의 여동생 Shannon은
she gradually shed the effect that the virtual internet had on her
사건 이후 조금씩 정신 네트워크의 영향으로부터 벗어나면서
and her condition started to improve
병세가 많이 호전되었다.
A.R.C. kept begging Xenon to return
A.R.C.는 끊임없이 Xenon에게 복귀할 것을 요청하고 있지만
But no matter how generous their offers were, no matter what position they promised
그들이 아무리 좋은 대우나 직위를 제안한다고 해도
Xenon refused to accept
Xenon은 시종일관 그 제안을 무시하고 있다.
After the dissolution of Baro,
Baro 패거리가 와해된 후, JOEZ Cafe의 입지는 조금씩 올라가고 있으며
JOE's way of doing things became more and more like Saxon's
JOE의 모습에서도 조금씩 Saxon의 모습을 볼 수 있게 됐다.
Mr. Neumann decided to move to Node 13,
ConneR는 Node 13으로의 이주를 결정하고
continuing to research the unsolved mysteries of his ancestors with Sasha
Sasha와 함께 아직 풀지 못한 자신의 조상에 대한 역사와 수수께끼를 연구하기로 했다.
Humanity was still curious about ancient technology and yearned to learn more
인간의 고대 문명에 대한 흥미를 잃어버린 것은 아니었다.
The missions of A.R.C.'s Exploration Team continued
A.R.C.의 탐사대는 여전이 임무를 수행 중이다.
ConneR：Oh? You again?
ConneR：뭐야? 당신이었나?
ConneR：Keep up the hard work
ConneR：수고가 많군.
Rin was able to break free of A.R.C.'s control,
Rin은 A.R.C.의 지배로부터 벗어나
concealing her Architect identity and living with Sagar
아키텍트의 신분을 숨기며 Sagar와 함께 생활하며
She also returned to Node 03 to look for her past memories
그녀 역시 Node 03으로 돌아와 과거 기억의 단서를 쫓고 있다.
Rin：Ah! Oh...
Rin：아앗!.....
Rin：I'm s-so sorry!
Rin：죄, 죄송합니다!
Rin：Wah!
Rin：꺅!
Daigo：Chief, here's the part you asked for
Daigo：팀장, 찾으시던 부품 여깄습니다.
Nora returned to Kyuu Hou Kai and led research in various fields of medicine
Nora는 구황회로 돌아와 각종 의료 기술 연구를 주도하고 있다.
Nora：Thank you, just put it there
Nora：고마워, 거기에 놔두도록 해.
all the while trying to repair ROBO_Head
그리고 동시에 ROBO_Head의 수리를 계속해서 진행하고 있다.
Nora："NORA"
Nora：「NORA」
Helena was unable to accept the loss of PAFF and Noah, remaining mired in sorrow,
Helena는 PAFF와 Noah의 일로 깊은 슬픔에 빠져있다. 그리고
all alone
혼자라는 외로움 속에도.
Hayato remained in the "music world", as promised,
Hayato는 약속했던 [음악 세계]에 머물며
missing Kaori through music
음악을 통해 Kaori를 추억한다.
Though sorrow and regret remains,
비록 슬픔이 계속 가시지 않더라도.
everyone is still working hard to live their lives
하지만 사람들은 열심히 살아가기 위해 노력하고 있다.
The world still turns,
세상은 계속 돌아갈 것이다.
just as before.
지금까지도, 앞으로도.